# **Chude Steve Nnamdi**

I am a proactive, smart, driven software engineer with 4 years of development experience. I have developed software solutions for business use cases from conceptualization to deployment. I am a proficient React.Js, Next.Js, Angular.Js, NodeJs, JavaScript and TypeScript developer. Softwares i have built includes Fintech Payment Website, Health Tech solution, logistics web app, etc. I have great communication skills, problem solving, decision making and I am a team player.

Alhaji Arije's compound, off Zimest avenue, Greenville Estate. Ajah Badore, Lagos State.

+2348089147905

Email: <a href="mailto:stevechude@gmail.com">stevechude@gmail.com</a>
Github: <a href="mailto:https://github.com/stevechude@gmail.com">https://github.com/stevechude@gmail.com</a>

<u>ude</u>

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.co m/in/steve-chude-6734a7191/ website: https://steve-chude.verce l.app/

## **EXPERIENCE**

## **Tezza Business Solution,** Lagos — Frontend Developer (Contract)

OCTOBER 2023 - PRESENT

- Building several web applications, including a Test Data management app that a telecom company can use in testing their products before distribution.
- Team Lead of the development team.
- Working with Next Js Framework and Tailwind CSS.
- Optimizing the app and improving its performance.
- API Integration with the backend server built with Node.Js.

# **HuiosPay Limited,** Abuja — Frontend Developer (Remote)

MAY 2023 - PRESENT

- Building the Payslate web app which is a multipurpose payment platform for customers to sign up on and make easy payments for eg: (school fees, rent, subscriptions, etc).
- Working with Next Js Framework and Tailwind CSS.
- API Integration with the backend server to implement all functionalities as relates to the Payslate website.

## **Talosmart Limited,** Lagos – NextJS Developer (Contract)

APRIL 2023 - August 2023

- Member of a team building the Switch Hive website, where users can make mobile top-ups, buy gift cards and pay bills with crypto.
- Built the Blog post section
- Built the Gift Cards flow, where users can view the info on a selected card and add to their cart for purchase.
- Built the modal for Sign up and Login.
- Consuming API endpoints built with NodeJs and Web3

# **Bottleking Nigeria Ltd**, Lagos — Fullstack Developer (Hybrid)

AUGUST 2022 - DECEMBER 2022

- Responsible for implementing the new UI designs for the company's e-commerce website with React js and consumed all backend API's built in Node js.
- Built a new landing page and a new user authentication pages including (sign up, login, logout, email verification pages) and added timed pop ups for newsletter sign up, blogs and company give-aways, all mobile responsive.

# **TECHNOLOGIES**

- HTML 5
- CSS 3
- Tailwind
- Javascript
- Typescript
- React is
- Next js
- Angular
- RxJs
- Redux
- React Hooks
- Nodejs
- Express Framework
- NestJs
- GraphQL
- MongoDB
- Postgresql
- Heroku
- Firebase
- Jira
- Docker
- Version Control with Git and Github.
- Test-Driven
   Development.
- Agile Methodologies.

#### **CERTIFICATIONS**

 SCRUM Certified Fundamentals

- Implemented a new Google signup and login feature to quickly onboard a new customer on the company's website.
- Maintained the old website built in Next js and installed google ad tracking and conversion codes for google analytics.
- Installed Meta pixel codes for facebook ads and tracking and domain verification.

## **Decagon**, Lagos — Software Engineer (Onsite)

OCTOBER 2021 - AUGUST 2022

- A member of a team that built dispatch buddy, a logistics web app.
- A member of a team that developed LightPay, a blockchain wallet app.
- Working on Client Projects and Building Internal tools primarily with TypeScript and the MERN Stack.
- Implemented a Transfer service API with TypeScript, Node.js, Express.js, Docker, MongoDB
- Built use-able react components in react.js and styled with CSS.
- Built dozens of REST API with ExpressJS and NestJS.
- Exposure to agile methodologies.

#### **PROJECTS**

#### **PAYSLATE APP:**

A modern payment solution app that has 2 user journeys (Organization & Users). A company can open a payslate account to easily receive payments from their customers, while an individual can open a payslate account to easily connect with multiple organizations registered on the platform and make payments to them.

**Technologies Used -** Next Js, Tailwind, Javascript, Redux, Java.

Link - https://www.payslate.com.ng/

# **SWITCH HIVE WEBSITE (TEST DESIGN):**

A platform where users can spend crypto in a fast and easy way while earning points by referrals. Make mobile top-ups, buy gift cards and pay bills with crypto for over 1000 products globally.

**Technologies Used -** Next Js, TailwindCSS, Vercel, Node.js, Web3.

Link

https://switch-hive-frontend-ofnfpx84a-talosmart-monodome-frontend.vercel.app/

#### **GIFT CARD LANDING PAGE:**

A fully responsive landing page of a GiftCard website from Figma Design, built and styled in 6 days with Next Js and TailwindCSS. Used GSAP library for animations.

**Technologies Used -** Next Js, TailwindCSS, GSAP, Vercel.

**Link -** https://gift-card-phi.vercel.app/

**NextJS BLOG WEBSITE:** 

A beautiful blog website built with Next Js and hosted on Vercel. With server

side rendering of a static database API file and dynamic page rendering of

each blog article. Styled with tailwind Css.

**Technologies Used -** Next Js, tailwind CSS, Vercel.

Link - https://blog-by-steve.vercel.app/

**CRYPTOBASE WEBSITE:** 

A responsive crypto website fetched from coingecko's api as third-party, built

with react is and styled with tailwind css, with an addition of a firebase

backend with full user authentications and route protections.

**Technologies Used -** React Js, tailwind CSS, Firebase, Coingecko API.

Link: https://crvptobase-website.netlifv.app/

**FOODMINE ANGULAR APP (IN PROGRESS):** 

A foodmine website built with angular, it represents a food commerce app

with the following features (view all available foods, view foods by categories,

click on a particular food, add food to cart, view cart page with all foods added

to cart). It is still missing an API server for user authentication (sign up and

login, payment and checkout page) though, but it is an awesome

representation of a food-commerce web application.

Technologies Used - Angular 14, CSS, NodeJS.

Link - <a href="https://foodmine-app.vercel.app/">https://foodmine-app.vercel.app/</a>

**BOTTLEKING WEBSITE (Staging environment):** 

A responsive website design deployed for testing on netlify.

**Technologies Used -** React js, CSS, Node js(backend)

**Link:** https://bottleking.vercel.app/

**EDUCATION** 

Federal University Of Technology Owerri — B.eng

OCTOBER 2012 - FEBRUARY 2017

Second Class - Bachelor of Engineering degree in Mechanical

Engineering From FUTO, Nigeria.